Abril Lamarque
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Scrapbooks, 1920-1959, undated, Series 10:; (boxes 7-10; 1.2 linear feet)
  This series contains seven scrapbooks with newspaper clippings, magazine articles, caricatures, illustrations, scattered letters, photographs, event invitations, and original artwork extensively documenting Lamarque's personal and professional life. Four scrapbooks include covers for magazines Lamarque designed as well as his published caricatures and illustrations for such magazines as Bally-hoo, Film Fun, Inside Detective, Modern Screen, Screen Romances, and others. Scrapbook 1 includes a copy of Lamarque's first cartoon published in 1921 and correspondence from Lamarque's lawyer regarding his application for a patent for his “radiocatures,” a radio broadcast that verbally transmitted his pictures and caricatures while the audience followed a diagram printed in the Telegram-Mail.
  Of special interest in Scrapbook 3 are two letters addressed to Cuban caricaturist and publisher Conrado Massaguer from Vanity Fair magazine expressing an interest in Abril Lamarque's artwork. Examples of Lamarque's business stationary are also found in this scrapbook. Scrapbook 4 is devoted to artwork Lamarque created for the Dell Publishing Company, including advertisements designed by Lamarque for Ballantine Ale, a beer company owned by George T. Delacorte, owner of the Dell Publishing Company.
  Scrapbooks 5 and 7 document Lamarque's interest in magic and his numerous performances as an amateur magician in connection with the Society of American Magicians and the International Brotherhood of Magicians. Scrapbook 6 contains clippings of book reviews for Brooklyn U.S.A., written by John Richmond and Abril Lamarque.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1920-1951, undated (Box 7 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 2, 1920-1939, undated (Box 7 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 3, 1924 -1951, undated (Box 7 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 4, Dell Publishing Company, 1927-1930, undated (Box 8 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 5, 1936-1958, undated (Box 8 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 6, 1940-1959, undated (Box 9 (sol))
  - Scrapbook 7, 1942-1958, undated (Box 9 (sol))
  - Original artwork removed from Scrapbook 1, undated (Box 10 (sol))